<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About Me on cjsommer.com</title><link>https://www.cjsommer.com/tags/about-me/</link><description>Recent content in About Me on cjsommer.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cjsommer.com/tags/about-me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>So Long, Olo!</title><link>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2025-09-23-soo-long-olo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2025-09-23-soo-long-olo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t blogged in quite some time but figured this was post worthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s with a heavy heart that I share that I was among those impacted by the recent layoffs at &lt;a href="https://www.olo.com/"&gt;Olo&lt;/a&gt;. December would’ve marked six years with the company—but sadly my time there has come to an end. I had the privilege of working alongside many incredible people, and I will truly miss working with all of you. &amp;#x1f979;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>So I have a new home! Welcome to cjsommer.com part deux!</title><link>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2017-03-03-so-i-have-a-new-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2017-03-03-so-i-have-a-new-home/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to put a quick post out there for the people who follow me. I very recently made a switch from Wordpress to Jekyll blogging platform and I am certain it will come with a few hiccups. At the moment I don&amp;rsquo;t have comments enabled, although I hope to add that feature this weekend. Also I do need to go through all of my posts and make sure images and code snippets all look how they&amp;rsquo;re supposed to. That will definitely be a work in progress for a bit as I have a number of posts to go through.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ponderings of PASS Summit 2016</title><link>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2016-11-03-ponderings-of-pass-summit-2016/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2016-11-03-ponderings-of-pass-summit-2016/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summit 2013 in Charlotte, NC was my first and I remember it well. I went with 4 other people from my company but I was pretty new to the SQL PASS community (otherwise known as #sqlfamily). As a matter of fact I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know what #sqlfamily was at this point. I went to all of the PASS sponsored events like the welcome reception, the vendor party and yes the NASCAR party (which being a NASCAR fan was awesome). I went to all of the sessions and generally hung out with the other people from my company. I did get a taste of the after-life a bit, but for the most part I stayed in my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Who is cjsommer?</title><link>https://www.cjsommer.com/page/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cjsommer.com/page/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a problem solver as far back as I can remember, always looking for a new challenge. I love staying current in technology, pushing the software to its limits, as well as finding its boundaries. For me there is satisfaction in knowing the answer to something because you have tried it out yourself. So a bit about me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Unix, Windows, Informix, Oracle, SQL Server. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in small shops. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in large shops. I&amp;rsquo;ve made lots of coffee. I&amp;rsquo;ve drank lots of coffee. I&amp;rsquo;ve had good on call weeks, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had bad on call weeks. Okay, you probably get it; I have a diverse background. Do I know everything? Absolutely not! What I do know is that I still have that hunger for knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Who is cjsommer?</title><link>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2015-03-24-who-is-cjsommer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2015-03-24-who-is-cjsommer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a problem solver as far back as I can remember, always looking for a new challenge. I love staying current in technology, pushing the software to its limits, as well as finding its boundaries. For me there is satisfaction in knowing the answer to something because you have tried it out yourself. So a bit about me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Unix, Windows, Informix, Oracle, SQL Server. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in small shops. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in large shops. I&amp;rsquo;ve made lots of coffee. I&amp;rsquo;ve drank lots of coffee. I&amp;rsquo;ve had good on call weeks, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had bad on call weeks. Okay, you probably get it; I have a diverse background. Do I know everything? Absolutely not! What I do know is that I still have that hunger for knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Specialty</title><link>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2015-03-24-my-specialty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 17:16:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.cjsommer.com/post/2015-03-24-my-specialty/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So I was reading the following &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;blog post by Brent Ozar&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and I think it finally hit me right between the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think from a DBA perspective I would have to consider myself in the DevOPS realm, but more generally, I am an automation specialist. It&amp;rsquo;s what I truly love to do and where I shine. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a simple information gathering exercise, or deploying database code, I enjoy automating it. Automation brings simplicity, scalability, consistency and reliability to a potentially complex process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>